Commander to all units:
[無線]（涯）コマンダーより
全ユニット。→
集が　いのりのヴォイドで
足止めをする。→
Shu will hold them in place with Inori's Void.
During that time, we'll seize the second truck.
その間に
２台目のトラックを奪取する。
[無線]（鶫）ターゲット　攻撃ポイントまで
あと　６・５・４・３・２・１→
The target will be at the attack
point in 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1...
ゴー！
Go!
（集）あっ！
Shu, what's wrong?!
[無線]（涯）集。　どうした？
[無線]（アルゴ）おい。　まだかよ？
Hey, what's the holdup?
Please, make it quick! They'll spot us!
[無線]（アルゴ）早くしてくれ。
バレちまうぞ！
（集）駄目だ…。
[無線]（アルゴ）ちっ！　バレた。
I can't!
Dammit, they spotted us!
[無線]（鶫）集！
どうしたの？　応えて！
Shu, what's wrong?! Answer me!
At this rate, everyone will!
[無線]（鶫）このままじゃ　みんなが…！[無線]（アルゴ）早く来てくれ！！
Come quick!
（いのり）集。
Shu.
うわぁぁぁぁ！！
集！
Shu?!
[無線]（涯）コマンダーより
全ユニット。→
Commander to all units:
abort the mission! Abort the mission!
ミッション　アボート。
ミッション　アボート！
So, everything that makes me whole
♪♪～
I'll now give to you
I'm yours
Say, there's lots of happiness
in this world, isn't there?
Someday, if we're together
Even if someone calls you a liar
And tries to hurt you with heartless words
Even if the world tries to make
you wear a crown of thorns
Without even trying to believe in you
I can take your side, and yours alone
I know that solitude, that pain
So, everything that makes me whole
I'll now give to you
- Blooming wildflower
degeneration
♪♪～
- Do you love me, Shu?
- Blooming wildflower
（真名）《集。　私のこと好き？》
《うん》
- Yeah!
- I beg you, please tell me
（真名）《じゃあ　約束して？
お姉ちゃんを幸せにするって》
- Then promise me something.
- I beg you, please tell me
- Promise you'll make your big sister happy.
♪♪～
Summer's sun clouded over, the wind streamed by
The two overlapped
ハッ！
ハァ～。
Shu!
（祭）集。　起きた？
上がるよー。
Are you awake? I'm coming up!
（祭）おはよ　集。
よく眠れた？
Morning, Shu! Did you sleep well?
Here.
（祭）はい。
"Bakery Cowbell"
Breakfast. It's a sandwich; is that okay?
朝ご飯
サンドイッチだけど　よかった？
うん…。
You surprised me yesterday, you know,
（祭）昨日は　びっくりしたんだよ。
突然　「助けて」ってメールが来て。
when you messaged me
out of nowhere asking for help.
You're not going to tell me anything?
何も教えてくれないの？
Why don't you want to go home?
どうして
おうちに帰りたくないの？
Well, you can tell me when you feel like it...
言いたくなったらで　いいけど…。
（着信音）
（祭）出ないの？
You're not going to answer?
（呼び出し音）
I see.
（涯）そうか。
いや　取りあえず放置しておけ。
No, let him be for now.
（涯）集のやつ…。
That Shu...
I apologize for the wait.
（亞里沙）お待たせしました。
（亞里沙）
お久しぶりですわね　恙神さん。
It's been a while, hasn't it,
Mr. Tsutsugami?
"Gai."
「涯」と。
仲間は　皆　そう呼ぶので。
All my comrades call me that.
"Report on the Investigation of Gai Tsutsugami"
（供奉院）驚いたよ。
This is a surprise. I certainly
never thought you were his son.
（供奉院）まさか　君が
あの男の息子だったとはなぁ。
（亞里沙）《「あの男」？》
"His"?
Which means I have to ask you:
（供奉院）故に
わしは問わねばならん。
恙神　涯。　君は
なぜ　何のために戦うのだね？
Gai Tsutsugami,
why do you fight? What is it for?
It's for a woman.
女のためです。
There's one special woman out
there that I want to hold in my arms.
たった１人の女を
この手で抱きたい。
That's why I'm fighting.
だから戦っています。
ハハハハ！→
日本を救うのは　女のついでか！
面白い。
Saving Japan is a side project to
getting your woman, eh? Now that's funny!
例の石は　明後日に
羽田に持ち込まれる。
The rock we discussed will be brought
to Haneda the day after tomorrow.
ヤンは　どうやら　石を　海外に
運び出そうとしているようだ。→
It seems Yan is trying to transport it overseas.
あれは
日本人が握っているべきものだ。
It's something that should
remain in the grasp of the Japanese.
Don't you think so?
そうは思わんかね？
ええ。　全力で阻止します。
Yes. We'll bend all our powers to stopping them.
（ヤン）
まさか　各国垂ぜんの　この石が→
Who would have thought this rock,
the object of every nation's desire,
こんなふうに
転がり込んでくるとはな。
would fall into my hands like this...
This will take you another
step closer to the White House.
（エミリー）これで　あなたは　もう一歩
ホワイトハウスに近づけますわね。
You're an ambitious woman, Emily.
（ヤン）君は野心家だ　エミリー。
（エミリー）ウフッ。
分からんのは　茎道か。→
I suppose the unknown is Keido.
石を盗み出し　逃亡するかと思えばのこのこ戻ってくるとは…。
He steals this, and then instead
of running he waltzes right back here?
I'm so glad you feel like
coming back to school, Shu!
（祭）よかった。　集が
授業　出る気になってくれて。→
I mean, it's really not good for
you to hole up in that place forever.
ずっと　あそこに　こもってるの
やっぱり　よくないもん。　ねっ？
Right?
うん…。
いのりは休みなんだよね。
Uh-huh.
Inori's... out today, right?
Yo!
（颯太）よう！　集　来たのか。
Shu, so you're here!
Where've you been, man?
お前　今まで　何してたんだよ。
あ…　いや…。
Um...
（生徒）キャッ！
ごめん　大丈夫？
Sorry! Are you okay?!
Um, sure, sorry...
あ…　いや。　すいません。
うわぁぁ！！
（祭）集！？
Shu?!
あっ！　あぁぁぁぁ！
（祭）どうしたの？　大丈夫！？
What's wrong? Are you okay?!
"Blockade Zone"
（祭）お水　取ってきてあげる。
待ってて。
I'll go get you some water.
You wait here.
What's the matter with you?
（綾瀬）どうしちゃったのよ？
あんた。
綾瀬さん…。
Ayase...
やめたいんです　もう。
（綾瀬）あんた　まさか→
I'm done. I want to quit.
Don't tell me you're ready
to give up on everything
キャンサー化した子供を
１人救えなかったぐらいで→
just because you couldn't
save one kid with the cancer?
全部　諦めようっての？
I thought I could do it.
できると思ったんだ。
僕は変わった。　だから　僕だって
涯みたいにできるって…。
I've changed. So I thought
I could work things like Gai.
But...
なのに…　僕は僕だった。
I was just me. I could only be Shu Ouma.
どうしようもなく
桜満　集だったんだ。
I can't believe you're wallowing
in that "poor tragic me" crap!
（綾瀬）何　悲劇の僕に酔ってるの！
いいかげん
目を覚ましなさいよ　集！
Wake up already, Shu!
It's no use, Ayase.
無駄だ！　綾瀬。
Please, wait. Give me just a little more...
（綾瀬）
待ってください　もう少しだけ。
奪われた　はじまりの石の
所在が判明した。
We know where the stolen
"rock that started it all" is.
奪還作戦を仕掛ける。　来い。
We're running a recovery mission.
Come on.
It's got nothing to do with me!
知らないよ　そんなの！
（綾瀬）集！
Shu!
I never wanted this stupid
power in the first place!
だいたい　僕は　こんな力
欲しくなかったんだ！！
I'm sick of it, do you hear me?
もう嫌なんだよ。　こんな…。
They say it's possible to isolate
the Void Genom if its possessor dies.
ヴォイドゲノムは　所有者が死ねば分離できる可能性があるという。
試すか？
（綾瀬）あっ！
Want to test that?
これで　お前は死人だ。
You're a dead man now.
Don't show your face in front of us again.
二度と
俺たちの前に　顔を見せるな。
いのりも引き揚げさせる。
I'll have Inori pull out, too.
意気地なし！　一瞬でも
仲間だと思った　私がバカだったわ！
Coward!
I was stupid to think for even
a second that you were one of us!
まだ…　いたんだ。
You're still here, huh?
U-Um, telephone calls or
texts or something... can we...
あ…　あの…　電話とか　メールとかその…。
これ　新しい歌なの。
Here.
This is a new song.
I'd like you to listen to it, Shu.
よかったら聴いて　集。
Shu.
（真名）《集…。　集》
うわぁぁ　化け物！
Monster!
ごめん！　何か　僕…。
I'm sorry! I'm just sort of...
It doesn't matter anymore.
いいの　もう。
Goodbye, Shu.
さよなら　集。
I think I must've wanted to be like Gai.
《たぶん　僕は　涯みたいに
なりたかったんだと思う》
《でも　無理だった。
だから　これで　いいんだ》
But it was impossible.
So it's better this way.
That's right. Everything's gone back to normal.
《そうさ。　全部　元通り》
《これで　いいはずなのに…》
It should be better this way, but...
しょっぱいよ　いのり…。
It's too salty, Inori.
（ダン）ヤン少将は　重要機密と共にあの機で一時帰国される。→
Major General Yan will be temporarily
returning home on that craft
with some top-secret materials.
無事　送り出すのが
俺たちの任務だ。
Our duty is to see him safely off!
締まっていこうぜー！！
なっ！　ハハハハ！
Let's do this thing! Right, men?
（嘘界）そろそろ
少将が到着されるころですねぇ。
The Major General should
be arriving any minute now.
≪（エレベーターの到着音）
あっ！
（ダリル）あっ！
ダリル…。
Daryl...
（ダリル）うっ！！
♪♪～
《周期が短くなっている》
The cycle is getting short.
Am I... near my limit?
《限界が近いか…》
涯。
Gai.
Am I... a monster?
私は化け物？
集に言われたのか。
Did Shu tell you that?
Did you fall in love with him?
好きになったのか？
あいつのことが。
≪（カーテンの開く音）
これが…　好き？
Is this..."love"?
Tell me, Gai, do I love Shu?
ねえ　涯。
私　好きなの？　集のこと。
《やはり　お前も
あいつを選ぶのか》
So you choose him too, in the end.
Survive first.
まずは生き延びろ。
話は　それからだ。
We'll think about this afterward.
（バイブレーターの音）
（祭）あの！
Excuse me!
（春夏）どういうつもりなんです！？
茎道局長！→
What do you mean by this, Chief Keido?!
クロスのＩＤを使って
あの石を盗み出して→
How could you use Kurosu's ID to steal that rock,
not to mention hand it
over to Major General Yan?!
しかも　それを
ヤン少将に引き渡すなんて！
（茎道）フッ。
島で懐かしい顔を見たよ。→
I saw a familiar face on the island.
He's grown a lot, hasn't he?
ずいぶん大きくなっていたね。
Don't involve Shu in this!
（春夏）集を巻き込まないで！
もう遅い。
It's too late for that. He's already
succeeded to the king's power.
彼は継承した。　王の力を。
Shu has... the Void Genom?
集が…　ヴォイドゲノムを！？
That's not all. He's in with Funeral Parlor, too.
（茎道）それだけじゃない。
彼は　葬儀社にも参加しているよ。
（茎道）楪　いのり。
君も会ったろう。→
Inori Yuzuriha. You've met her too, haven't you?
あの顔　あの姿をした少女が→
Do you really believe a girl
with that face, that body,
ただの偶然で
彼の隣にいると思うのかね？
is by his side through mere coincidence?
涯…。
Gai.
All right. Begin the operation.
よし。　作戦開始。
「ポイントＢまで　あと３０」
We'll be at Point B in 30.
Aye!
（鶫）アイ！　そこからは
こっちじゃ操作できない→
After that point there are
surveillance cameras and monitors
監視カメラや　モニターがあるから注意して！
that I can't control from here, so be careful.
コマンダーより　全ユニット。
Commander to all units:
目標の輸送機の離陸まで
あと３０分だ。
We have thirty minutes until our
objective's transport plane takes off.
My team will seize the plane before then.
それまでに
俺たちが　機体を奪取する。
The Endlave unit will deploy when
we announce the seizure and back us up.
エンドレイヴ部隊は　機体奪取の
知らせと同時に展開し援護を。
Got it?
いいな？
（綾瀬）「了解です」
（鶫）アイ！
Roger.
Aye!
You summoned me out here too,
so don't screw it up.
（城戸）僕まで呼びつけたんだから
しくじらないでよ。
Of course not.
無論だ。
（ダン）お待ちしておりました。
ヤン少将。
We've been expecting you, Major General Yan!
（ヤン）例の輸送機の
準備は　どうか？
Is the transport plane ready?
Yes, Sir! Everything's been fully prepared
はっ！　嘘界少佐の指揮の下→
準備万端　整っております。
under Major Segai's careful command.
（嘘界）
カメラのチャンネルをＧ７に。
Switch the camera to channel G7.
There's no such channel, Sir...
そのような回線は
存在しませんが？
Well, naturally. After all, I just now set it up.
当たり前です。
先ほど　私が仕掛けたのですから。
Here we go.
あ　よいしょ。
（嘘界）ビンゴ。→
Bingo.
Are we ready for broadcast?
中継の準備は？
（士官）完了しています。→
All set, Sir.
It'll be outputted from every channel
in the city that's under GHQ control.
都内のＧＨＱ管理下の
全回線から出力されます。
Excellent.
結構。
こちら嘘界少佐。
親愛なるアンチボディズの諸君→
This is Major Segai. All my beloved
members of the Anti Bodies,
ワクチンＤを接種せよ。→
take Vaccine D now.
I repeat: All my beloved
members of the Anti Bodies,
繰り返す。　親愛なるアンチボディズの諸君ワクチンＤを接種せよ。
take Vaccine D now.
♪♪～
What happened?!
（兵士）どうした！？
♪♪～
（嘘界）茎道局長。
これで　よろしいのですね？
I trust this will do, Chief Keido?
Don't come crying to me later.
僕は知りませんよ。
（城戸）涯たちは？
（鶫）大丈夫。　機内に潜入してるわ。
How's Gai's team?
Fine. They've boarded the plane.
《静か過ぎるか…》
It's too quiet.
But... it's too late to back out now.
《いまさら　後戻りはできん》
（アルゴ）あっ！→
無人！？
It's unmanned?
どういうことだ！
What does this mean?
（嘘界）恙神　涯！！
Gai Tsutsugami!
君を天国へ～！！
I'm sending you to heaven!
≪♪♪（歌声）
What's going on here?
何なんだ！　これは…。
何ぃ！？
What?!
♪♪（歌声）
（祭）授業
最後まで聞きたかったな。
I wish I'd gotten to hear the rest of the lecture.
私　古文　結構　好きなんだよ。
そうなんだ。
I like Classics a lot, you know.
Oh, huh...
Come on, I say so all the time!
いつも　言ってるじゃない。
な…　何？
What?
近くにいさせてよ　祭。
Let me be close to you, Hare.
You don't mind, right?
いいでしょ？
After all... you love me, don't you?
だって　祭は→
僕のこと好きなんだよね？
（祭）集！
Shu!
は…　祭！
Hare!
ごめん　祭！
I'm sorry, Hare!
（祭）何が？
えっ？
For what?!
Try telling me exactly what you did wrong!
（祭）何が悪かったのか
自分で言ってみて！？
Um...
えっと…。
See, you don't know!
（祭）ほら　分かってない！→
集は
私のこと　全然　見てない…。→
You're not seeing me at all, Shu.
Don't make me a substitute for Yuzuriha!
私を　楪さんの代わりにしないで！
そんなつもりは…。
I didn't mean to...
集は　すごい力を持って→
Did your big new power make it
so you can't even see yourself anymore?
自分のことも
見えなくなっちゃったの？→
私　見たの。→
I saw it.
集が　谷尋君から
はさみみたいの取り出して→
I saw you draw something like scissors
out of Yahiro and bust an Endlave.
エンドレイヴを壊すの。
あのときの集が　かわいそうで…。
I felt so bad for you then...
And I wanted to help cheer you up somehow...
何とか励ましてあげたいって
思ったけど…。→
でも　そんな集じゃ　嫌！
But that Shu just now wasn't okay!
そんなの　私の好きな集じゃない！
That's not the Shu I love!
（泣き声）
ごめんね　祭。
I'm sorry, Hare.
I really am sorry.
本当に　ごめんね。
何だ？　今の…。
What was that?
≪♪♪（歌声）
This is... a song?
これは…　歌！？
≪♪♪（歌声）
ぐっ！！　ぐぐぐぐ～！
（アルゴ）くそっ！！
操縦が利かねえ！
Crap, the controls don't work!
Tsugumi, cut the remote controls!
鶫。　遠隔操作を切れ。
[無線]（鶫）ちょい待って！
Gimme a sec.
ぐぐっ！
[無線]（鶫）遮断完了！
Done!
This is genetic resonance!
これは！　遺伝子共鳴。
まさか！
石を発動させたというのか！
Don't tell me he's activated the stone?!
（オペレーター）ぐわぁぁぁ！！
No!
嫌だ！
うわぁぁぁ！！
≪（銃声）
（春夏）あっ！
（ローワン）お迎えに上がりました。
I've come to fetch you...
（ローワン）局長。
...Chief.
Gai!
涯！
（大雲）アルゴ！　前！
Argo! Look out!
（アルゴ）んっ！！
綾姉　逃げてー！
Aya, run!
（春夏）いったい　何を
考えているんです！？　あなたは！
What can you possibly be thinking of?!
人類の未来を。
Humanity's future.
Now, let's begin.
さあ　始めよう。
Let's finish what we started on
that day... on that Christmas we lost!
あの日…
あの失われたクリスマスの続きを。
≪♪♪（歌声）
What's this bad feeling?
何だ？　この嫌な感じ。
まるで…。
It's just like...
≪♪♪（歌声）
駄目。　やめて…。
No... Stop!
This isn't the right song!
この歌じゃないの…。
起きてしまう。
She'll... wake up!
あの人が…。
≪♪♪（歌声）
うぅ！！　あぁ！！
Really, Shuichiro,
you're old enough to know better.
（ユウ）年がいもなく
いくつもりですか？　修一郎。
You're as entertaining as always.
相変わらず　楽しい人ですね。
キャー！
（人々の悲鳴）
駄目っ！！
No!
I'll never be loved by you again
♪♪～
Or needed by you again, either
And so here I am, all alone
What did you say that day?
Words that'll never be heard flutter in the air
Even though I know better,
I can't help making another
Hopeless wish today
Keep holding my hand tight and don't let go
Tell me you'll stay with me
Your hand in mine was warm and kind